♪Peach blossoms fall,
yesterday's trace fades away♪
♪Ahead lie storms and winds,
our fates like drifting clouds sway♪
♪Alas, I roam through what remains,
fate's grip won't set me free♪
♪If time would spare me
just one breath to stay♪
♪If you could see
the depth of my belief♪
♪Alone I enter the game,
every move made with no regret in me♪
♪Though shackles bind my soul
and chain my form♪
♪I've walked
through life and death before♪
♪I fear not fate's cruel temptations,
I've severed every cause♪
♪In this life our threads entwined,
in love and pain we crossed♪
♪But I'll keep my word
no matter the cost♪
♪Forged in stardust and flame♪
♪I rise with an unyielding frame♪
=The Princess's Gambit=
(Adapted from the novel "Peach Blossoms
Reflecting the River and Mountains")
(by Bai Lu Cheng Shuang)
=Episode 36=
(Outside the Imperial Prison)
Will this plan work?
Even if you don't trust the Chancellor,
don't you at least trust
the Princess?
Report!
Your Highness,
they killed the guards outside.
But they didn't enter.
What?
I didn't see Jiang Changjue either.
Cui Wei, take your men
and launch a counterattack.
Try to capture them alive.
If Qian Mochen isn't enough
to lure him out,
we'll catch a few more.
Jiang Changjue
will show up sooner or later.
Yes, Your Highness.
Follow me!
Stop them
and buy the Chancellor some time.
Wait!
Watch them closely.
Your Highness,
I saw Qingtai
and Shen Zaiye's guards.
Jiang Taohua and Shen Zaiye
have returned to Hao City?
What were you doing?
How could you not detect even
a hint of it?
It was my failure in duty.
But
I didn't see them myself.
I only overheard the guard saying,
"Hold them off
and buy the Chancellor some time."
"Hold them off"?
Could they have discovered
Qian Mochen's location?
Check the hidden sand cave now.
Yes, Your Highness.
Chancellor. Your Highness.
As expected, Cui Wei left in a hurry
through the back entrance
with a few men.
They took the bait.
Then we should make a move
to pick up the State Preceptor.
Is something troubling you?
Is the poison acting up?
No.
Then what's the matter?
Nothing.
I'm just scared.
Taohua,
don't worry.
I'm here.
Changjue,
you stay here.
We'll go check it out.
All right.
The four of you, come with me.
Commander Cui.
Any unusual activity?
Commander Cui, everything is clear, sir.
Send a letter to Her Highness
to inform her that nothing is unusual.
Yes, sir.
Follow him.
This way.
Wait here.
Go and inform Changjue
and set the ambush.
Yes, sir.
(Secret transport. Palace now.)
We need to lure Empress Lv to this spot.
(Safe and secure.
Proceed with the siege.)
(Proceed with the siege)
Who's there?
Stop them.
- Yes, sir.
I'll hold off Cui Wei.
You find Qian Mochen.
Be careful.
Master.
I…
I told An Chu
not to let you get involved.
How could I abandon you?
Changjue has been praying
for your safe return.
At least,
you're finally calling me
"Master" again.
Have you found
Changjue?
Yes.
Good.
The three of us
have finally put the past behind us.
All that's left is to reunite.
Your safety is all that matters.
I protected you
and your brother
out of gratitude to the late Empress.
Now,
I've repaid the kindness I owed.
So I have no regrets now.
You should be happy
for me.
Master,
you once said,
"True courage is knowing
something is impossible
and doing it anyway."
So today,
I will get you out of here.
Report!
Your Highness, we received a message
from the hidden sand cave.
They've called for reinforcements.
Mobilize everyone
and head to the hidden sand cave.
Yes, Your Highness.
Cui Wei may return at any moment.
Master, we must go now.
Unlocking the chains takes time.
Leave me.
Use your wrist as a pivot
and slowly release pressure
through your fingers.
Now! Charge!
Kill him!
(Darn it.)
(Of all times,
the poison flares up now.)
Your Highness.
It's an ambush!
Protect Her Highness!
Fall back! Move!
- Charge!
- Kill them!
Kill!
(Jiang Changjue.)
(No, this was a trap!)
Kill him now!
If Empress Lv finds out he's alive,
we're dead!
The key
is a steady hand.
The lock's tumblers
must flow like water.
I've unlocked it.
Fight your way out!
Escort me back to the palace!
Empress Lv,
you caused the Luocheng massacre,
which led innocent people
to lose their homes and lives.
You murdered
my mother!
You also poisoned
my sister!
You're ruthless and heartless!
Heaven itself won't forgive you!
Empress Lv,
do you admit your crimes?
Who are you to judge me?
Whoever kills Jiang Changjue
will be generously rewarded!
- Kill!
Kill!
Retreat! Head east!
Empress Lv is here! Take her down!
Move!
Head north!
- Kill!
Kill them all!
Empress Lv, stop running!
Empress Lv,
this is your end.
Fate has decided it.
Why keep struggling?
Hand over the antidote,
and I'll leave your body whole.
Never.
If I'm going down,
I'm dragging Jiang Taohua with me!
Kill him!
Let's go to the secret tunnel
in the northwest.
Master,
this way.
Here, let me help you.
Master!
Chancellor,
you are…
I'm fine.
Are you all right?
I'm all right.
Master.
Empress Lv?
Stop right there!
Princess.
The antidote.
Go and get it.
But…
I'll be fine.
Go ahead.
Go.
Master,
wait for me right here.
All right.
Jiang Taohua,
we meet again.
Empress Lv,
there's no escape this time.
Today will be the day you die.
Who's to say I couldn't escape?
Maybe I just didn't want to.
You've committed countless atrocities.
Now, retribution has finally come
for you.
Retribution?
Oh, spare me the righteousness.
Who are you to stand for justice
and judge me as if I'm pure evil?
Listen.
I rose to the height of power
through my efforts.
How is that wrong?
You're blind to your sins
and shameless.
Empress Lv,
you're at your end.
Hand over Yinghuo.
So you've learned about Yinghuo.
That means Mei Ling is in your hands.
Don't trust her.
She won't give it to us.
What a touching couple you two make.
How disgusting.
Are you jealous?
You could've had all this.
My father favored you.
Yet you wanted more.
Mu Wuyin loved you deeply.
But you only used him.
What a joke!
Do you think I care about love?
If I were jealous of you,
it was your birthright.
Jiang Taohua,
you were born a princess,
protected by your noble family.
What would you know of my ambition?
Your father,
the so-called Emperor,
was a lustful fool.
Mu Wuyin was the son of an Emperor.
But he was weak and useless.
What do they have that I don't
besides noble birth?
Why should I bow to any of you?
I clawed my way to the top.
I'll rule this world!
No one
will ever step on me again!
Even without noble birth,
what makes you better than them?
You murdered loyal officials,
stole from the people,
and lived in luxury
while the people starved.
You've ruled Beiyuan into the ground
all these years.
The people are in misery,
and the state is crumbling.
Your downfall
is your own making.
What do you know?
You know nothing!
I had a grand vision for this land!
Chancellor,
no point talking sense with her.
She won't change.
Those are…
Yinghuo.
You want Yinghuo?
In your dreams!
I've already doused
this entire place in oil.
I'll burn Yinghuo to ash
right before your eyes!
Shen Zaiye,
I want you to watch
Jiang Taohua die in agony
because of your incompetence!
Finally starting to lose hope?
Die! All of you!
If it weren't for you,
I would've already ruled the world!
So long as you're dead,
no one in this world can stop me!
Taohua! Chancellor Shen! Lift this!
Taohua, lift it!
Qian Mochen, you traitor!
Master!
Taohua,
don't worry about me.
Just lift it!
You want to save her?
In your dreams!
Master!
Taohua, use more force!
Qian Mochen can't hold out much longer!
You can do it!
Go now!
Master!
Go! Run! Master! Live, Taohua.
Get out of here now!
Master.
You must live.
Go!
(Three days later)
Taohua,
you're awake.
Your Highness.
Taohua.
Do you want to get up?
Let me help.
Physician Mei, quickly!
Water…
Drink slowly.
Since Her Highness has awakened,
the poison from the Jiangtao Pill
must've been neutralized.
Really?
I'll prepare
some medicinal meals for you.
With a few days of rest,
you'll be back to full health.
Neutralized?
But Yinghuo was burned to ashes.
Qingtai,
where's the Chancellor?
(That day, Chancellor risked his life
to retrieve a single stalk of Yinghuo.)
(But it wasn't enough for both of you.)
♪The brokenness buried in my brow♪
(For you,)
(he chose the lesser of the two.)
♪Save for the slow crown
beneath whispered lips♪
♪With no one to carry dreams
across the rivers wide♪
(But he still has residual poisons
in his body from testing medicines.)
(They're all mixed and complex.)
(He's now unconscious.)
(Physician Mei said,)
(we're just using medicine)
(to keep him alive for now)
(and hold on as long as we can.)
♪I was the one who had to take it away♪
♪You weren't falling,
no need to feel all the sorrow and joy♪
♪I wasn't someone meant
to wait and hope♪
♪Don't blame my affection
for bringing you cold winds♪
♪We were both unwilling to give in♪
♪Who would've thought♪
♪It began as a trial by fate♪
♪Yet it turned into a fleeting bond,
lost to time♪
♪Worn out from wandering,
with no shelter to rest beneath♪
♪You never complained♪
♪And I lay awake♪
♪Who ever pitied us♪
♪In those long, cold, uncertain years?♪
♪What I offer now♪
(Jiang Taohua,)
(just remember)
(that no matter what happens,)
(you can always trust me.)
♪Where petals fall and quiet words
are spoken over a game♪
♪Tears draw out more tears
and what's seen is not truly seen♪
♪If you walk away, looking back♪
♪How many more years will I lose again?♪
Your Highness,
the Chancellor asked me
to give you this.
What is it?
Yinghuo seeds.
(Yinghuo needs
very specific conditions to grow.)
(It grows deep in the desert caves.)
(The moisture levels)
(and changes in the sandy soil)
(can affect its growth.)
(Yinghuo is an extremely cold
and yin-based plant.)
(Without the moonlight to sustain it,)
(it may never bloom.)
♪I'm lost for words when you turn away♪
♪The closer our fluttering hearts
draw near, the more they try to hide♪
♪The deeper my thoughts grow
for you at night♪
♪The more afraid I am of losing you♪
♪Your eyes sparkle like the stars
that adorn the night♪
♪Ever so bright, ever so pure♪
♪Reflecting all beneath
the heavens and the earth♪
♪Because of you,
every scene is beautiful♪
♪Though fierce winds rage,
the candle's flame burns warm♪
♪Etching our longing into a vow♪
♪Though parting looms,
no price too great to pay♪
♪In life and death,
our hearts will never stray♪
♪Those simple, ordinary days♪
♪Feel like a dream of mine♪
♪Humble meals a day♪
♪Far away from worldly concerns♪
♪Those memories become clear over time♪
♪The long night passes in a flash♪
(Heaven above,)
(Shen Zaiye was poisoned)
(because of me.)
(Tonight, I ask)
(for a bit of moonlight.)
(So Yinghuo may bloom.)
(I, Taohua,)
(would give my life)
(to light a lamp for Shen Zaiye.)
(So he may live out his days in peace,)
(free from all worries.)
♪Ever so bright, ever so pure♪
♪Reflecting all beneath
the heavens and the earth♪
♪Because of you,
every scene is beautiful♪
♪Though fierce winds rage,
the candle's flame burns warm♪
♪Etching our longing into a vow♪
♪Though parting looms,
no price too great to pay♪
♪In life and death,
our hearts will never stray♪
♪Those simple, ordinary days♪
♪Gazing at nature
and recalling all those who flourished♪
♪In that fleeting moment,
it felt as if I'd seen it all ♪
♪A glimpse of eternity♪
♪Those memories become clear over time♪
♪Soft and endless like silken threads♪
♪Driven by fate, an undying past♪
♪Unfazed by the ending♪
Physician Mei,
why hasn't he woken up
after taking the antidote?
The poison had already reached
his organs.
The damage it left behind
won't heal so easily.
His body is like a battlefield now.
The poison
and the antidote fought it out.
The antidote may have won the fight.
But what's left is a land torn by war.
Healing will take time.
Physician Mei,
is there any way to know how long?
That's the problem.
If we're lucky,
he could wake up tomorrow.
If not,
he may never wake again.
(Shen Zaiye,)
(however long it takes,)
(I'll be right here waiting.)
What are you thinking about?
In three months,
snow will fall again in Beiyuan.
I remember
it snowed all the way
from winter into spring one time.
I cried and begged
to see the peach blossoms.
So my mother carried me
and we watched the snow fall
beneath the peach blossom tree.
♪Alone I enter the game,
every move made with no regret in me♪
Snow falls every year.
It's not like you'll never see it again.
♪Though shackles
bind my soul and chain my form♪
(You're right.)
(It's not like I'll never see it again.)
♪I fear not fate's cruel temptations,
I've severed every cause♪
♪In this life our threads entwined,
in love and pain we crossed♪
♪But I'll keep my word
no matter the cost♪
♪Forged in stardust and flame,
I rise with an unyielding frame♪
♪I take your hand without a doubt,
one move decides our world♪
(The End)
♪The flower bloomed,
knowing nothing at all♪
♪In splendor, proud and tall♪
♪The flower fell, lashed by the wind♪
♪In a daze,
it felt like lifetimes had thinned♪
♪Petals soaked in rain♪
♪Heartbreak follows again and again♪
♪The flower weeps, burdened by thoughts♪
♪With no one it can be brought♪
♪Wishes struggle through the mire♪
♪Regrets clash in hopeless fire♪
♪Still I hope she'll pick the flower
kissed by dew♪
♪Even if it means this flower♪
♪Will be hers to give to someone new♪
♪Whose eyes
did the flower's heart meet?♪
♪Love and hate held back, discreet♪
♪The flower withers, feelings in decay♪
♪No longer needing to say♪
♪Yet I still long for her in madness♪
♪Unafraid of judgment or sadness♪
♪Remembering the words
she spoke of flowers and skies♪
♪And finding♪
♪They were her gentle heart's reply♪